《哥谭》前情提要
Previously on Gotham...
去见了位认识的警员
Went to see a sergeant that I know,
我俩寻找了符合描述的M马龙
and we did some digging for any M. Malones that fit our particulars.
帕特里克·马龙
Patrick Malone.
绰号为..."火柴"
Goes by the nickname... Matches.
你找到他了
So you found him.
你要我做什么
What do you need me for?
我要你给我找把枪
I need you to get me a gun.
你想杀了他吗
So you're gonna kill him?
我爱你
I love you.
柯丽丝汀
Kristen.
不要
No!
如果连奥斯瓦尔德·科波特都能治好
If we can cure a man like Oswald Cobblepot,
那我们就能治愈任何人
we can cure anyone.
所有惹恼了企鹅的人都追悔莫及
Nobody yet has failed to regret vexing the Penguin.
而你正在惹恼我
And you are vexing me!
你不吃
You don't eat.
怎么了  亲爱的
What's the matter, liebchen?
你不舒服吗
You are sick?
你看上去如此苍白
So pale you look.
告诉妈妈怎么了
Tell Mama what's wrong.
你不用说出口
You don't have to tell.
我知道
I know.
特殊的人  人生之路必然坎坷
Life is hard when you are special.
你又是那么特殊
And you are so special.
那么聪明
So clever.
那么帅气
So handsome.
你长大后
When you are older,
得用棍子赶走成群的求爱女人了
with a stick you'll beat away the women.
但前提是你得吃菜炖牛肉
But only if you eat your goulash,
这样你才能长大...
so you can grow big...
变强
and strong.
将克兰配方和我们的强制快速眼动刺激相结合
Matching the Crane formula to our own enforced REM stimulation
似乎能达到理想的效果
seems to be providing the desired results.
他平日的表现如何
How's his behavior day-to-day?
温顺  友善
Docile, friendly.
胃口呢
Appetite?
不高  但我并不担心
Low, but I'm not concerned.
我想知道他对不良刺激会有何反应
I'm curious to see how he responds to adverse stimuli.
我们开始进行...冰淇淋测试吧
Let's move on to the... ice cream test.
冰淇淋
Ice cream.
为什么你有冰淇淋
Why do you have ice cream?
我也不知道
I'm sure I don't know.
很不寻常  是吧
It's unusual, isn't it?
我叫奥斯瓦尔德  你叫什么
My name's Oswald. What's yours?
我没有冰淇淋
I don't have ice cream.
为什么你有冰淇淋
Why do you have ice cream?
请吧  不要客气  你...
Please, by all means, you...
我没有冰淇淋
I don't have ice cream!
为什么你有冰淇淋
Why do you have ice cream?!
抱歉  先生  我不知道...
I apologize, sir. I don't know what...
非常好
Excellent.
没有暴力反应
No violent reaction.
治疗效果非常好
The treatment is working perfectly.
守卫
Guards.
我的冰淇淋在哪
Where's my ice cream?!
为什么你有冰淇淋
How come you have ice cream?!
我要我的
I want mine!
在哪  在哪
Where is it?! Where is it?!
我要我的冰淇淋
I want my ice cream!
是什么味儿的  什么味儿的
What flavor is it?! What flavor is it?!
仅供学习  禁止商用  更多影视
登陆www.ZiMuZu.tv
翻译 Silence   DustD   charcie   大K   小酸奶!   草草
后期 饿得慌   时间轴 风吹来的那片云   校对&总监 草草
你也好啊
Hey yourself.
怎么了  你问我要的
What? You asked me for it.
我知道
I know.
-如果你不想要...  -我要
- If you don't want it... - I want it.
你看上去很害怕
You look scared.
我没有
I'm not.
上膛了吗
Is it loaded?
不上膛的枪有什么意义
Ain't no point in an unloaded gun.
枪可不是用来唬人的  布鲁斯
Guns aren't for show, Bruce.
也不是用来防身的
And they're not for protection.
只有一个用处
They're only for one thing.
当然了
Of course.
只有一个用处
They're only for one thing.
哥谭
第二季  第十四集
小莱
Lee.
早上好
Good morning.
阿卡姆那事之后我们说的话
Look, what we talked about after Arkham...
我不是来谈那个的
That's not why I'm here.
我想你看看这个
I wanted you to take a look at these.
这是柯丽丝汀·柯林格最后几张工资单
It's Kristen Kringle's final paychecks.
她的工资单  你是怎么拿到的
Her paychecks? How'd you get these?
我去人力资源部要她的新住址
I went to Human Resources to get her new address,
他们就把工资单给了我
and they gave them to me.
她一直没去领
She never picked them up.
他们也不知道她的下落
They don't know where she is.
她没兑现过  也没留下转寄地址
She never cashed them, never left a forwarding address.
这就奇怪了
That's odd.
多尔蒂有钱
Well, Dougherty has money.
也许他们去旅游了
Maybe they're traveling.
事情不对劲
I don't like it.
她说多尔蒂曾对她家暴
She said that Dougherty hurt her before.
真的吗
Really?
你问过爱德吗
Have you talked to Ed about it?
-没  -也许他有她的消息
- No. - Maybe he's heard from her.
我不想让他担心
I didn't feel like it was right to worry him.
我只是想知道她没事
I just want to know that she's all right.
我可以交给失踪人口去查
I can take it to Missing Persons.
不不  没事  我会去查的
No, no, that's all right. I'll look into it.
有消息通知你
I'll let you know what I find.
谢谢
Thank you.
没事
Yeah.
布鲁斯少爷
Oh, Master Bruce.
准备好了吗
You ready?
好了
Yes.
这样的语气可不够
I'm gonna need more than that.
我们要去寻找一个极度危险的人
We're on the hunt of an extremely dangerous man.
这是生死攸关的事
This is life-and-death stuff.
我要你给我确定的答案
I need you to tell me that you are sure.
你确定你准备好了吗
Now, are you sure?
是的  阿尔弗雷德  我确定
Yes, Alfred, I'm sure.
好
Right.
出了门  你要完全听从我的指示
And when we're on the street, you follow my every lead.
不许乱冲乱撞  明白吗
No faffing about, is that understood?
明白
Yes.
好孩子
Good lad.
我们的目标是个东区人
Our quarry is an East Side boy.
"火柴"帕特里克·马龙年少就误入歧途
His misspent youth, Patrick "Matches" Malone
曾多次跟一个叫小蛋糕的家伙一起被捕
was arrested several times with a geezer called Cupcake.
已知同伙  特伦斯·肖  又名小蛋糕
我怀疑这有一定的讽刺意味
I suspect there's irony at play there.
他们曾是共犯  直到"火柴"的证词
They were partners in crime until Matches's testimony
害小蛋糕先生蹲了十年黑门监狱
put Mr. Cupcake in a Blackgate Pen for ten.
上面写着小蛋糕已经出狱
Says here that Cupcake's out now,
开了家叫做变异体的打手公司
and he runs this strong-arm little firm called the Mutants.
我们就从那里开始吧
So I guess we'll have to start there then.
-所罗门  -格伦迪
- Solomon! - Grundy!
记住  我来说话
Remember, let me do the talking.
我知道怎么对付这种人
I know how to handle this type, all right?
女士们先生们  下午好
Good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen!
你们好
Hope we find you well.
我们想跟小蛋糕先生
We're hoping to have a little chat
说两句话
with a gentleman called Cupcake.
我在这里  亲爱的
You found me, sweetheart.
什么事
What's up?
小蛋糕先生  幸会
Mr. Cupcake, pleasure to meet you.
我叫阿尔弗雷德·潘尼沃斯
My name's Alfred Pennyworth.
我们在找一个叫"火柴"马龙的人
Now, we're on the hunt for a guy called Matches Malone.
我们知道几年前  他向警方告发了你
Now, we know he snitched you up a few years ago.
所以你大概不介意"回报"他一下
So I'm sure you wouldn't mind returning the favor,
如果你懂我意思的话
if you know what I mean.
你朋友是谁
Who's your friend?
-别管他是谁  -我是布鲁斯·韦恩
- Never mind who he is. - I'm Bruce Wayne.
少年亿万富翁布鲁斯·韦恩
Boy billionaire Bruce Wayne?
正是
That one.
我愿意付你一大笔钱
I'm willing to pay you a lot of money
只求你告诉我马龙在哪
if you can tell us where to find Malone.
真的吗  为什么
Oh, really? Why?
布鲁斯少爷  请让我...
Master Bruce, please let me...
我认为他杀了我父母
I think he killed my parents.
这回答不错
That's a good answer.
你出多少钱
How much money?
出多少能让你开口
How much will make you talk?
一百万美元
Million dollars.
太多了
That's too much.
这孩子还挺抠门
The boy's cheap.
小蛋糕先生  请恕我斗胆...
Mr. Cupcake, if I may be so bold as to just...
我在和做主的说话呢
Yo, I'm talking to the shot caller.
这样吧  孩子  我和你做个交易
Tell you what, son, I'll make you a deal.
给我五万美元  你得不到"火柴"
Give me $50,000, you won't get Matches,
但是你可以完好无损地离开这里
but you get to leave here with your fingers and toes.
慢着  老兄
Steady on, pal.
我逗你玩呢
I'm just messing with you.
我不会伤害小孩的
I wouldn't hurt the little boy.
我喜欢小男孩
I like little boys.
至于你  就未必了
You, on the other hand, I'm not sure about you.
这样吧  五万  我就说出那叛徒的下落
Tell you what, I'll give you that rat Matches for 50 grand.
但首先
But first...
你得和我打一场
you must fight me.
不好意思  你说什么
I beg your pardon, excuse me?
和我打一场  宝贝
Fight me, baby.
不  你看  我不是个...
No, you see, I'm not really a, uh...
我不怎么打架
I'm not really a fighter.
得了  你刚刚不是挺身而出了
Shush, I saw you step up just now.
"慢着  老兄"
"Steady on, pal."
小蛋糕先生  我真看不出这场争斗
Mr. Cupcake, I really can't foresee anything positive
能产生什么好结果
coming out of this altercation.
你在我的地盘
You're in my house!
我们这里就是要打
Fight is what we do here!
我给你十万  买名字但不打架
I'll pay you $100,000 for the name and no fighting.
我要的不是钱  小孩
I'm not about money, little boy.
我要的是尊重
I'm about respect.
不打  不成交
No fight, no deal,
不给"火柴"  别想离开
no Matches, no exit.
那好吧
All right, well, I suppose, you know,
小蛋糕先生  既然你都这么说了
Mr. Cupcake, if you put it like that.
劳烦您一下  先生
If you wouldn't mind, sir.
你会没事吧
Will you be all right?
那只能等着瞧了  是不是
We'll have to wait and see, won't we?
你是想说这是我的错吗
Are you acting like this is my fault?
这话轮不到我说  对吧  先生
It's not for me to say, is it, sir?
这怎么是我的错了
How is it my fault?
我说了让我来谈  对不对
I told you to let me do the talking, did I not?
但最终你是不是说话了  没错
And did you do the talking? Yes.
没错  你就是说了
I think you'll find, yes, you did do the talking.
说实话  我觉得不管怎样
To be fair, I think the result
结果可能都差不多
would have been similar in any case.
如果  布鲁斯少爷  我们够幸运
If, Master Bruce, we are lucky enough
能从这里活着出去
to walk away from this alive,
请从中吸取教训
let this be a lesson to you.
还有一件事
And another thing.
有选择地战斗
Pick your battles.
别受其所制
Don't let them pick you.
好了
Right!
以你的名誉担保  我赢了...
On your honor, I win...
放我们走
we walk.
当然了  先生
Sure thing, mister.
以我的名誉担保
On my honor.
他们会理解的
They'll understand.
但是除非有人
But the fight doesn't stop
服软或被打晕  才算结束
till somebody says uncle or goes to sleep.
开始吧
Now get it on.
当然了  布鲁斯少爷  另一件要记住的事
The other thing, of course, Master Bruce, to remember
是时机就是一切
is that timing is everything.
还有其他决定因素  布鲁斯少爷
See, there's other factors at play there, Master Bruce.
那就是步法和巧劲
There's footwork and leverage.
闭嘴
Stop talking!
怎么了  怎么了  你想尝尝吗
What?! What, you want some?!
阿尔弗雷德
Alfred!
服软  服软
Uncle! Uncle!
不
No!
他的动作在变慢
He's slowing!
你看  布鲁斯少爷  块头越大消耗越大
See, Master Bruce, big muscles require lots of blood.
越有劲  越易累
Strength costs wind.
如果你要击倒一个大块头
Now, if you're gonna beat a big man,
你只要...
all you have to do...
耗过他
is outlast him.
放开我  不...
Go! No...
服软  服软
Uncle, uncle.
服软了  管家赢了
Uncle! And the butler wins.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
我一点问题都没有  伙计
I'm absolutely flippin' peachy, mate.
你真是个顽强的老家伙
You're a tough old cat.
你也不赖啊  小蛋糕先生
Not too shabby yourself, Mr. Cupcake.
火柴
Matches.
五万
50 grand.
支票可以吗
Will-will a check be all right?
行行  支票没问题
Yeah, yeah, sure, a check'll be fine.
只写金额就行
Make it out to cash.
去东区的天堂花园找杰瑞吧
Go see Jeri down at Celestial Gardens on the East Side.
她知道上哪找火柴
She'll know where to find Matches.
跟你做生意很愉快  小蛋糕先生
Pleasure doing business with you, Mr. Cupcake.
你感觉怎么样
How do you feel?
休息个几小时  我就又生龙活虎了
A couple of hours' kip and I'll come up lovely.
很好
Good.
你待在这儿
You stay here.
哪也不要去
You ain't going nowhere...
等我恢复了再说  好吗
till I'm up and about. Eh?
好的  我知道了
Yes, I hear you.
向我保证  小布少爷
Promise me, Master B.
你说什么
Say again?
向我...
Prom...
对不起
Sorry.
血
Blood.
生命
Life.
喉咙
Throat.
歌
Song.
猫
Cat.
小猫
Kitten.
母亲
Mother.
拥抱
Hug.
罪恶
Crime.
惩罚
Punishment.
报仇
Revenge.
后悔
Remorse.
Ah, remorse.
咱谈谈这个吧
Let's talk about that.
我感觉到了  非常后悔
I feel it. A lot.
感到后悔是个进展
Remorse is progress.
这非常重要
Remorse is huge.
是吗
Is it?
我对一些事很过意不去  我...
I feel terrible about stuff. I...
我以前太坏了
I was so mean to people.
后悔是对人状态的健康自然的反应
Remorse is a healthy and natural response of the human condition.
这是好现象
It is a good sign.
是正常现象
It is a normal sign.
我想做个正常人
I want to be normal.
我想做个好人
I want to be good.
你一定以为我在说谎
You must think I'm lying to you.
不
Oh, no.
是不是说谎  我看得出来
I can tell when someone's lying to me.
奥斯瓦尔德  你的转变很巨大
Oswald, you are making a magnificent transformation.
真实的你正在显现
Your real self is emerging.
一个善良正直的年轻人
A kind, decent young man.
再有几个疗程  你就能治愈了
Just a few more therapy sessions and you'll be right as rain.
还要治疗
More therapy?
不多了
Oh, just a little.
我知道  你有不适感
I know there's a discomfort factor,
但毕竟  你在好转
but after all, it is making you better.
对吧
Yes?
你确实想好起来吧
Oh, you do want to get better...
是不是
don't you?
想  斯特兰奇教授
Yes, Professor Strange.
奥斯瓦尔德  得了
Oswald, please.
叫我雨果就行
Call me Hugo.
好  雨果
Yes, Hugo.
爱德  在忙吗
Hey, Ed, you busy?
我在研究各种颜色墨汁的分解率
I'm studying decomp rate of various colors of ink
看看能不能用文身判定死亡时间
to see if we can use tattoos to help determine time of death.
到底忙不忙
Is that a yes or a no?
请进
Please come in.
有什么需要
How can I help you?
想问问你最近有没有柯丽丝汀·柯林格的消息
I was wondering if you'd heard from Kristen Kringle lately.
我坚如磐石  但一言就足以毁灭我
I'm strong as a rock, but a word can destroy me.
我是什么
What am I?
沉默
Silence.
我没她的消息
I've heard nothing.
我不想吓你
Well, I don't want to alarm you,
但我们找不到她人
but we can't seem to locate her.
她上几次工资都没领
She hasn't cashed her last few paychecks.
我的天
Oh, my Lord.
你...
Do you...
你觉得她遭遇不测了吗
do you think that something bad has happened?
不  至少我们现在还没那么想
No. No, no, we're not there yet, anyway.
"我们"  "我们"是谁
"We"? Who is "We"?
我和我的好奇心罢了
Oh, just me and my curiosity.
我跟汤姆·多尔蒂不熟
I don't know Tom Dougherty well.
他人什么样
What is he like?
汤姆·多尔蒂什么样
What is Tom Dougherty like?
坏到骨子里
Rotten.
我也听人这么说
That's what I'd heard.
柯林格亲口跟你说
And Kringle told you herself
她要跟多尔蒂搬去南方吗
that she was moving south with Dougherty?
没当面说
Not in person.
她留了张字条
She left a note.
我能看下字条吗
Could I take a look at it?
我觉得没必要留着就扔了
I didn't really think of it as a keepsake.
好吧
Right.
我接个电话
Uh, excuse me.
怎么了
Yeah.
又来吗
Again?
好
Yeah, okay.
我这就过去
I'm on my way.
想跟我玩是吧  吉姆
So that's the game, is it, Jimbo?
想智胜我吗
Gonna try to outsmart me?
把我当白痴吗
Play me for a fool?
休想
I don't think so.
你们怎么才来
Well, that took you long enough.
你这个管家怎么总被人揍啊
For a butler, you sure do get beat up a lot.
怎么回事
What happened?
我们查到他的名字了  吉姆
We got his name, Jim.
那个杀害布鲁斯父母的真凶
The name of the man that killed Bruce's parents.
"火柴"马龙
Matches Malone.
哥们  我们才是警察啊
Dude, we're the cops.
多谢告诉我们这消息
Thank you for sharing this with us.
你怎么没早点说
When were you gonna tell us?
我没时间解释了
I haven't got time to explain them.
我们在我被人狠揍的地方
We got a good, solid lead from the same place
得到了一条可靠线索
that I got seven bells knocked out of me.
布鲁斯  他不接电话
Now Bruce, he won't answer his phone,
所以我猜他是去对付这个马龙了
so my guess is he's gone after this Malone...
一个人去了
solo.
"对付"
"Gone after"?
他要去干什么
To do what, exactly?
他能干什么  他还是个孩子
What can he do? He's a kid.
他单独行动的唯一理由就是
Only reason to go alone--
他要杀了那人
he's gonna kill the man.
我让他别这么做
I mean, I-I told him not to.
我说  "你还小  不能背上条人命"
I said, "You're too young for killing."
我说我会替他杀人
Said I'd do it for him.
再说一次  我们是警察啊
Again, we're the cops.
杀人这种事就别跟我们说了
Do not tell us stuff like this.
你们得理解...
You've got to understand, both of you...
这不是儿戏
this is not a game.
我理解
I understand.
告诉我他在哪
Tell me where he is.
天堂花园
小屁孩儿
Hey, cowboy.
先生
Yes, sir.
玩得开心
Have fun.
*我心潮涌动*
*I got a feeling inside of me*
*有些离奇  感觉如惊涛骇浪*
*It's kind of strange, like a stormy sea*
疯子帮
疯子帮大闹哥谭市警局
*不知为何  不知为何*
*I don't know why, I don't know why*
*大概也只能如此*
*I guess these things have got to be*
*得到新玫瑰  她拜倒我膝下*
*I got a new rose, I got her good*
什么叫正常
*我想我早知道会如此*
*Guess I knew that I always would*
*游戏人生  停不下来*
*I can't stop to mess around*
*新玫瑰驾到*
*I got a brand-new rose in town*
你好  布鲁斯
Hello, Bruce.
怎么才来
What took you so long?
我找杰瑞
I'm looking for Jeri.
我知道
Yeah, you are.
跟我来
Follow me.
过来
Come.
随便坐
Take a pew.
冰茶  苏打水
Iced tea? Soda?
不  谢了
No, thank you.
你喜欢我的表演吗
You like the show?
我喜欢
I liked it.
你是杰瑞吗
Are you Jeri?
有人那么称呼我
Some people call me that.
怎么了
What?
你有什么事
What can I do for you?
抱歉  你知道我的名字
Sorry. You know my name,
那么小蛋糕打给了你
so Cupcake called you.
我以为你已经知道我为什么会来了
I assumed you already know why I'm here.
我只是想让你说出来
I just want you to say it.
我在找"火柴"马龙
I'm looking for Matches Malone.
为什么
Why?
他杀了我的父母
He killed my parents.
你找到他后准备怎么办
What you gonna do if you find him?
问他一些问题
Ask him some questions...
然后杀了他
...kill him.
抱歉  抱歉
Okay, I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
杀人
Killing people
并不是那么简单的事
isn't, you know, that easy.
也许你之前杀过人
Hey, maybe you've killed people before.
你以前杀过人吗  小家伙
You killed people before, blood?
没有
No.
但以前也没人杀过我父母
But no one's killed my parents before.
火柴杀过很多人
Well, Matches has killed dozens of people.
有男有女...
Men, women...
还有孩子...
children...
他是专业的
He's a professional.
你到底算什么
And what, exactly, are you?
你知道他在哪吗
Do you know where he is?
我当然知道他在哪
Course I know where he is;
他是我朋友
he's a friend of mine.
你倒是给我个充分理由告诉你他在哪
You gonna give me a good reason to tell you where he is?
正义
Justice.
得了吧
Please.
-钱  -不
- Money. - Nope.
我不在乎钱
I don't care about money.
试试别的理由
Try something else.
我有枪
I have a gun.
这理由不错
That's a good reason.
拜托你
Please.
告诉我他在哪
Tell me where he is.
孩子...你还没拿枪指着我呢
Come on, kid... you ain't even pointing it at me!
你到底怎么回事
What is your problem?
有人告诉我  如果你没打算开枪
I've been told it's unwise to point a gun at someone
就不该拿枪指着人
if you're not ready to shoot them.
而我没这打算
And I'm not.
非常明智  年轻人
Very wise young man.
谢谢你  杰瑞
Thank you, Jeri.
跟你...
It's been...
聊天...很有意思
interesting... talking to you.
火柴住在
Matches lives
格兰特大街九大道和十大道之间的那幢大房子里
in that big building on Grand Street between 9th and 10th.
9B号公寓
Apartment 9B.
你为什么要告诉我
Why did you tell me that?
他不是你的朋友吗
I thought he was your friend.
没错
He is.
曾经是
Well, he was.
火柴见到你肯定高兴
Matches is gonna be happy to see you.
你  就是一双稚嫩的命运之手
You, my boy, are the childish hand of fate.
那我也算是上帝了  不是吗
Well, that makes me God in a way, doesn't it?
谁不喜欢扮演上帝啊
And who doesn't like to play God?
自由
布鲁斯
Bruce!
请放开我
Please let me go.
布鲁斯  听我说
Bruce, listen to me.
我知道你想做什么
I know what you're doing.
阿尔弗雷德都告诉我了
Alfred told me everything.
他不该那么做的
He shouldn't have done that.
我理解你的感受
I understand how you feel.
不  你不理解
No, you don't.
的确  我是不理解
No, you're right. I don't.
这无所谓  你只能走到这一步了
And it doesn't matter. This is as far as you go.
之后你要接手了吗
You're gonna take over from here, are you?
是的
Yes, I am.
抱歉  戈登警探
I'm sorry, Detective Gordon.
这并不能让我安心
That doesn't reassure me.
布鲁斯  我不能让你这么做
Bruce, I can't let you do this.
哥谭市警局  一二三四
GCPD! One, two, three, four!
*得到新玫瑰  她拜倒我膝下*
*I got a new rose, I got her good*
*我想我早知道会如此*
*Guess I knew that I always would*
*游戏人生  停不下来*
*I can't stop to mess around*
*新玫瑰驾到*
*I got a brand-new rose in town*
*看太阳啊  如此闪亮*
*See the sun, see the sun, it shines...*
"火柴"马龙
Matches Malone?
我想雇用你
I want to hire you.
现在的孩子啊
Kids now.
你想雇我
So, you want to hire me?
我想要一个人死
I want someone to die.
等等吧  那人会死的
Wait a while. They will.
我不想等
I don't want to wait.
你这就雇凶杀人  有点小了吧
You're kind of young to be putting out a contract.
我够大了
I'm old enough.
你是个经验丰富的杀手吗
Are you a proficient killer?
你不是说想雇我吗
I thought you wanted to hire me.
没说还要面试啊
You didn't say nothing about a job interview.
我得确定我雇对了人
I have to be sure I'm getting the right man.
你看到杀手还分辨不出来吗
Don't you know a killer when you see one?
其实  你看上去很普通
Actually, you look very ordinary.
你杀过很多人吗
Have you killed a lot of people?
我杀过各种人
I kill all kind of folks.
什么样的都有
Just about every way you can.
有钱的  没钱的
Rich, poor,
有罪的  无辜的
guilty, innocent.
赤手  用刀  开枪
By hand, by blade, by gun.
我就烧死了一个人
Burn just one guy to death,
结果就一直被他们叫"火柴"
they call you Matches the rest of your days.
生活真有趣啊  是吧
Life's funny, isn't it?
怎么不说话
Cat got your tongue?
怎么  孩子  病了吗
What's the matter, kid-- you sick?
抱歉
Sorry.
我没事
I'm fine.
紧张而已
Nervous is all.
你似乎就是我要的人
You seem to be the right man.
当然了
Damn right I am.
布鲁斯·韦恩在哪
Where is Bruce Wayne?
你火气好大
You are so angry.
似乎有点私人关系
I'm sensing a personal relationship.
或许是代替父亲那样的
Maybe like a surrogate father type of thing.
他在哪
Where is he?
他...
He is...
他真是个好孩子
he's a really good kid.
他挺有骨气
He's got steel in him.
他有一日会成长为坚强的男人
He's gonna grow up and be a strong man one day.
如果他能活到那天的话
Well, if he lives long enough.
如果你不惹我生气
This is gonna go a lot better for you
对你会更好
if you don't make me angry.
你天生就是个气冲冲的人吧
Angry is your natural state, isn't it?
你不就是名声赫赫的吉姆·戈登吗
You are the infamous Jim Gordon?
大家都知道你的脾气
Everybody knows about your temper.
重点不是我
This isn't about me.
有个孩子现在身陷危险
There's a kid out there in danger.
好多孩子都有危险呢
Oh, there's lots of kids out there in danger!
为什么这个可怜的富二代那么让你上心
Why is this poor little rich boy got your special attention?
你是想激怒我
You're trying to make me angry.
你希望我伤害你吗
Do you want me to hurt you?
拜托了
Could you?
反正我也不用赶着去哪
I got nowhere else to be.
不
No.
马上告诉我你让布鲁斯·韦恩去哪了
Tell me where you sent Bruce Wayne-- now.
你可不如人家说的那么有意思
You are a lot less fun than advertised.
几点了
What time is it?
嗯  他这会儿应该到了
Yep, he should be there by now.
你刚好能赶过去收拾现场
So you could get there just in time for the cleanup.
杀一个成年男子
I starts at ten grand or so
起价一万左右
for a simple hit on an adult male vic.
根据难易程度
Then there's a sliding scale,
价格会有一定浮动
depending on how hard the job is.
女人要双倍
Charge double for women.
孩子要三倍
Triple for kids.
不杀婴儿
No babies.
我不杀婴儿
I won't kill babies.
"一万"
"Ten grand"?
不高啊
That's cheap.
开销低嘛
Hmm, low overhead.
你想要谁死  孩子
Who do you want dead, son?
你真不记得我了  是吗
You really don't remember me, do you?
记得你
Remember you?
不
No.
我们见过吗
We've met before?
是的
Yes.
我们见过
We've met before.
你杀了我父母
You killed my parents.
手放在我看得到的地方
Keep your hands where I can see them.
放心  孩子  我不会突袭你
Relax, kid. I won't jump you.
如果我想我是可以的  但是
I could if I wanted to, but...
我太累了
I'm too tired.
你是谁来着
Who are you, now?
我叫布鲁斯·韦恩
My name is Bruce Wayne.
我们什么时候见过来着
And when was this we met before?
两年前
Two years ago.
剧院区一条暗巷
An alley in the theater district.
你杀了我父亲和母亲  托马斯和玛莎·韦恩
You killed my mother and father, Thomas and Martha Wayne.
我当时也在
I was there.
有点印象
Rings a bell.
你当时直视了我
You looked right at me.
那年我活儿挺多的
Ah, I was busy that year.
我父母是重要人物
My parents were important people.
当时报纸大肆报导了一番
It was a big deal in all the newspapers.
我不怎么读报
I don't read the papers much.
也不看电视
Don't watch TV.
总是同样的坏消息
Always the same bad news.
你真不记得了
You really don't remember?
有些还是印象挺深刻的
Some of them stick with you.
有个小胡子男
There was this mustached fella.
爱哭的臭胖子
He was a big fat crybaby.
我经常梦到他
Comes back to me in my dreams all the time.
就好像他是什么重要人物
Like he's important.
我都不记得他叫什么了
I can't even recall his name.
我是捅死了他  把他丢下了屋顶
Did I stab him? Toss him off a roof?
我不记得了
I don't know.
我父母当时穿着晚礼服
My parents were in evening clothes.
那晚阴冷潮湿
It was cold and wet.
你一把抓过我母亲的珍珠项链  项链断了
You-you grabbed my mother's pearl necklace; it broke.
对了
Oh, yeah.
珠子撒了一地
And the beads went everywhere.
我现在想起来了
Coming back to me now.
挺漂亮的金发女人
It was a nice-looking blonde lady...
老帅哥型的男人和一个孩子
silver-fox-type dude and a kid.
那是你吗
That was you?
是我
That was me.
是谁雇了你
Who hired you?
或许没人雇我
Maybe nobody did.
或许我就是看到几个有钱的讨厌鬼
Maybe I just saw some rich suckers.
那样的人走进暗巷
Somebody like that walks into a dark alley,
他们就是活该  自己作死
they deserved it, 'cause they let it happen.
世界不就是这样吗  孩子
It's the way of the world, isn't it, son?
-别那么喊我  -怎么了
- Don't call me son. - Why?
如果我真做了你想的那种事
If I did what you think I did,
那就是我成就了现在的你
then I made you what you are.
就像哥谭造就了我
Just like Gotham made me.
就像你父母那样的有钱人造就了哥谭
Just like the rich folks like your parents made Gotham.
我为什么不能喊你"儿子"
I might as well call you son.
我可以逼你说出雇你的人
I can make you tell me who hired you.
是吗
You think so?
我可以伤害你
I can hurt you.
我可以打你的膝盖
I can shoot you in the knee.
或者腹部
Or the stomach.
但你还是逼不出一句话来
But you can't make me tell you a damn thing.
杀手原则不算什么
Killer's code ain't much,
但我只有这个
but it's what I've got.
如果我真做了你说的那件事
If I did what you say I did,
又是有人雇我去做
and someone hired me to do it,
你永远别想知道那人的名字
you'll never know their name.
除非你把我千刀万剐
Not if you take me apart piece by piece.
你最好信我
You better believe that.
那么就没什么可说的了
Well, then I guess there's nothing left to say.
敬你  孩子
Here's to you, son.
你早该来了
You've been a long time coming.
你希望我杀你
You want me to kill you.
为什么
Why?
你这种有钱小孩不会明白的
Little rich kid like you wouldn't understand.
说说看
Try me.
人会觉得厌倦
A man gets tired...
一直做坏事却不受惩罚
doing wrong and going unpunished.
没有任何后果
Nothing happens.
你会开始怀疑
You start to wonder if...
上帝真的存在吗
there is a God.
左手握紧
Tighten your left hand grip.
瞄准这里
Aim right here.
低一点
A little low.
枪有后坐力
She'll kick.
来吧  扣扳机吧
Come on, pull the damn trigger.
不
No.
别现在怂啊  动手
Don't lose your nerve now! Do it!
看着我
Look at me!
我是个禽兽
I'm a monster.
你得杀了我
You need to kill me.
我也希望你是个禽兽
I wish you were a monster.
但你只是个凡人
But you're just a man.
布鲁斯
Bruce!
他在里面
He's in there.
祝你好运  伙计
Good luck, buddy.
是不是搞错了
I think there's been a mistake!
谁在那儿
Who's there?
记得我吗
Remember me?
我是吃冰淇淋那个人
I'm the man with the ice cream?
对了
Oh, yeah.
是啊  你把我打得挺惨
Yeah, you knocked me around pretty good.
那冰淇淋一定很好吃吧
Guess that ice cream must be delicious, huh?
是挺好吃的
It was pretty good.
你似乎不太舒服
You look kind of uncomfortable.
我有把尖刀
I have a sharp knife here.
我帮帮你怎么样
What say I help you out?
帮我
Help me out?
你得保证会好好的
You have to promise to be nice, okay?
这里没有冰淇淋
There's no ice cream in here,
你没必要发火  好吗
so there's no reason to get mad, okay?
答应我
Promise?
好
Okay.
好了
There you go.
谢谢
Thank you.
好样的  科波特
Bravo, Cobblepot.
先生
Sir?
这是一份正式证书
This is an official certificate
由哥谭健康与卫生委员会签发
from the Gotham Board of Health and Hygiene.
上面写着奥斯瓦尔德·科波特
It states that Oswald Cobblepot
已经通过了所有强制测试
has passed all mandated tests,
依据哥谭市的法律
and by the laws of Gotham City
特此宣布已经精神正常
is hereby declared... sane.
我正常了
I'm sane?
你跟任何一位市民一样正常
You are as sane and normal as any other citizen.
甚至包括皮博迪女士
Ms. Peabody, even.
知道这意味着什么吗
Do you know what that means?
再不用做治疗了
No more therapy?
奥斯瓦尔德  你自由了
Oswald, you are a free man.
我不明白
I don't follow you.
你正常了
You are sane;
那么  你就没理由
ergo, there is no reason
继续留在疯人院了
for you to be in a mental health institution.
你可以离开了
You are free to go.
我待在这里挺好的
I'm fine right here.
奥斯瓦尔德  奥斯瓦尔德
Oswald, Oswald,Oswald,
你只是对改变有些焦虑
you are just feeling anxious about change.
这非常正常
That is totally normal
是对出院的正常反应
to feel that way upon release from care.
好吧
Okay.
如果是正常的话
I guess, if it's normal.
你是个精神正常
You are a sane,
性情温顺的好人
gentle, good man.
好人会遇到好事
And good things happen to good people.
是吗
They do?
这我从没听过
I-I've never heard that before.
是真的
A true thing.
相信我
Trust me.
到目前为止你都是对的
Well, you've been right so far.
谢谢你  教授...雨果
Thank you, Professor-- Hugo...
你是个好导师  好朋友
...for being such a kind mentor and friend.
真感人  奥斯瓦尔德
That's very touching, Oswald.
也谢谢你
Thank you so much.
现在
And now,
你回房去
why don't you go back to your room
收拾下你的东西吧
and get your belongings together?
好
Okay.
你真要这么做吗
Are you sure about that,
放他走
letting him go?
不  他是个实验
Not really. He's an experiment.
他是个臭名昭著的罪犯
He's a notorious criminal.
这会引起哗然
There'll be an outcry.
那会过去的
The outcry will pass.
人们害怕进步  皮博迪女士
People are afraid of progress, Ms. Peabody,
但我们还是不断前进
and yet, somehow, we keep progressing.
希望你至少通知下警方他已经出院
I hope you'll at least alert the police he's been released.
够了  皮博迪女士
Enough input, Ms. Peabody.
我自有理由
I have other reasons,
对科波特更深远的打算
deeper plans for Cobblepot,
而你现在不需要知道
that you can't know about now.
是为了你自己好
For your own safety.
更深远的计划
Deeper plans?
比造地下室里那些半人的东西更深吗
Deeper than building semi-human creatures in the basement?
那我肯定不想知道  多谢了
I'm sure I don't want to know, thank you very much.
你自己兜着吧
On your head be it.
我们没发现马龙可能是有原因的
There's a reason why we might have missed Malone.
他从幼儿园开始就有案底
Okay? His record goes back to nursery school on up--
袭人  抢劫  殴打
assault, robbery, battery,
几次替黑帮杀人
a couple of hits for the mob.
但这都是以前了
But this is way, way back.
这几年来  什么动静都没有
Last few years, nothing.
所以我们从未怀疑过他
That's why his name never came up as a potential suspect.
低调嘛  这也是有可能的
Flying under the radar, I guess. It happens.
看来我们无从知道是不是真是他了
Guess we'll never know if he really did it.
不  孩子说他承认了
Nah, the boy says he confessed.
这对我来说就够了
That's good enough for me.
马龙杀了韦恩夫妇
Malone killed the Waynes.
问题是  是谁雇他去杀韦恩夫妇的
The question is, who paid him to kill the Waynes?
这问题我已经不想去琢磨了
That's a question I no longer care to ponder.
爱德  你好吗
Hey, Ed. How you doing?
挺好的
Oh, getting along just fine.
忙活呗
Keeping busy.
柯林格的事有消息吗
Any news on the Kringle front?
没有
Uh, no.
真是的  抱歉
Damn. Sorry.
我有点忙来着
I've been a little busy.
我会去查的
I'll get into it.
别担心
Don't worry.
我  担心
Me, worry?
嗯  我有消息一定会马上告诉你
Yeah. I'll let you know as soon as I know anything.
戈登警探  有空吗
Detective Gordon, do you have a second?
嗯
Uh, yeah.
你会告诉我
You'll let me know.
当然了
I bet you will.
就好像你都忘记柯丽丝汀·柯林格了
Acting like you forgot all about Kristen Kringle.
你当然忘了
Sure you forgot.
你没问题的
You're ready.
谢谢  警探
Thanks, Detective.
你肯定怀疑我  肯定的
You suspect me somehow, that must be it.
你想哄骗我
You're trying to lull me
让我以为自己安全了
into a false sense of security
然后你调查的利爪
while the claws of your investigation
再渐渐收紧  是吗
close around me, eh?
是吗  小子
Is that it, my little man?
你当我是傻子吗
You take me to be a fool?
你的小诡计我们走着瞧  吉姆·戈登
We'll see about your clever little plan, Jim Gordon.
走着瞧
We'll see.
我自己也能想计策
I can make plans of my own.
布鲁斯少爷
Master Bruce!
阿尔弗雷德
"阿尔弗雷德
"Alfred,
我要离家一阵
I have left home for a while
去街上跟塞琳娜一起生活
to live on the streets with Selina.
求你别激动  先听我说完
Please, wait and listen before you react.
你不用担心我有危险
You need not worry that I'm in danger
或是疯了
or that I've lost my mind.
这事我好好想了很久
I've thought long and hard about this decision
我知道这么做没错
and I know it's the right one.
马龙的死让我明白了一些事
Malone's death made me realize a couple of things.
人无法杀死谋杀
You can't kill murder.
无法报复邪恶
You can't get revenge on evil.
只有不那么做  才是真正的与之抗争
You can only begin to fight such things by not doing them.
而且只能去他们滋生的地方与其抗争
And you can only fight them where they live,
不止是在韦恩集团
not just at Wayne Enterprises.
要去街头  贫民窟
In the streets, in the slums,
城里不那么好的地方
in the bad parts of town.
所以我要去那里"
So that's where I'm going."
他是疯了
He's lost his mind.
"我不会这就开始对付抢劫犯什么的
"I'm not going to start battling muggers or anything.
但有一日  我要想办法
But one day, I am going to do something
帮助哥谭人民
to help the people of Gotham.
我还不知道究竟要怎么做
I don't know what yet,
但我会做到的
but I will.
而现在  我得学习
Meantime, I need to learn stuff.
第一  我要学会
Number one: I need to learn
在很多其他人被迫生存的环境中生存
how to live in the same world other people have to live in.
塞琳娜给了我住的地方
Selina's giving me a place to sleep
而且答应教我怎么做
and will show me the ropes,
所以  就像我说的  你不用担心
so, like I say, there's no need to worry.
我会尽快联系你
I'll be in touch soon
我最终会回家的
and I'll come home eventually.
求你  阿尔弗雷德
Please, Alfred,
相信我  尊重我的意愿
trust me and honor my wishes.
别想把我找回来
Don't try to bring me back.
我必须这么做
I need to do this.
真诚的
Sincerely,
你的好友
your good friend
布鲁斯"
Bruce."
英雄警察授勋